<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<sst xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main" count="309" uniqueCount="292"><si><t>RELATED COURSES TO PURSUE IN COLLEGE</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Academic </t></si><si><t>Tech - Pro</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>STEM PATHWAY 1. Computer Science -</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> High aptitude in Logical Reasoning and Mathematical Ability with a Strong Inclination for Computational Problem-Solving and Digital Innovation. This suggests a preference for abstract design, algorithmic development, and systems thinking (Investigative &amp; Conventional/Realistic).</t></r></si><si><t>Software Development,
AI / Data Science, Digital Forensics, Computer Engineering</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Finite Mathematics 1,  Finite Mathematics 2, General Physics 1,  General Physics 2, Business 1,           Research Methods,               Fundamentals of Data Analytics,              Database Management             Design and Innovation     </t></si><si><t>Computer Programming(JAVA), Computer Programming(ORACLE), Computer Programming(.NET TECHNOLOGY), Electronics Product Assembly and Servicing</t></si><si><t>I am interested in writing clean, efficient code to build responsive and user-friendly software applications.</t></si><si><t>I want to delve into machine learning algorithms to create intelligent models that process vast datasets.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing and managing complex architectures for large-scale data storage and retrieval.</t></si><si><t>I want to study neural networks and natural language processing to develop systems that mimic human cognition.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by the full software development lifecycle, from gathering user requirements to system maintenance.</t></si><si><t>I want to optimize database queries and data warehousing techniques to drive business intelligence.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in specializing in front-end development using modern UI/UX design principles and frameworks.</t></si><si><t>I want to explore the mathematical foundations of cryptography to secure digital communication and data.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to build and train deep learning models for computer vision or autonomous system tasks.</t></si><si><t>I want to master DevOps practices to automate software delivery and improve infrastructure reliability.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in developing firmware and embedded systems for Internet of Things (IoT) devices.</t></si><si><t>I want to use statistical inference and A/B testing to guide digital product feature decisions.</t></si><si><t>I am keen on architecting scalable and fault-tolerant applications on global cloud computing platforms.</t></si><si><t>I want to explore ethical AI practices to ensure algorithms are fair, transparent, and socially responsible.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in developing video game engines and real-time graphics rendering algorithms.</t></si><si><t>I want to learn parallel computing techniques to optimize code for high-performance multi-core processors.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to develop recommender systems that personalize digital content for millions of users.</t></si><si><t>I want to learn compiler design and operating system internals to understand hardware-software interactions.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in creating interactive data visualization tools that make complex information understandable.</t></si><si><t>I want to use anomaly detection and machine learning to identify and prevent digital fraud.</t></si><si><t>RECOMMENDED ELECTIVES TO TAKE IN SSHS</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>STEM PATHWAY 2. Information Technology  -</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> High scores in Technical-Vocational Aptitude (Visual Manipulative Skills &amp; Clerical Ability) with a Strong Inclination for Systems Management and Security. This indicates strength in practical application, data organization, and network defense (Realistic &amp; Conventional).</t></r></si><si><t>IT, ICT Support, Computer Programming,  Bioinformatics, Mangement Information System, Cybersecurity, Network Administration, Systems Analysis</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Finite Mathematics 1 &amp; 2, Business 1 &amp; 2,  Research Methods,               Fundamentals of Data Analytics,              Database Management             Design and Innovation     </t></si><si><t>Animation, Illustration, Visual Graphic Design, Computer Programming(JAVA), Computer Programming(ORACLE), Computer Programming(.NET TECHNOLOGY),  Broadband Installation</t></si><si><t>I am driven to identify security vulnerabilities through ethical hacking and penetration testing.</t></si><si><t>I want to design and maintain secure enterprise networks to ensure continuous business operations.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in bridging the gap between business needs and technological IT infrastructure solutions.</t></si><si><t>I want to create disaster recovery plans and intrusion detection systems to protect organizational data.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by server virtualization and cloud storage management for global digital services.</t></si><si><t>I want to specialize in digital forensics to investigate and recover data after security breaches.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in managing large-scale IT projects using agile and waterfall methodologies.</t></si><si><t>I want to configure and secure wireless networks and VPNs for remote employee access.</t></si><si><t>I am keen on performing cost-benefit analyses for IT hardware and software procurement.</t></si><si><t>I want to implement Identity and Access Management (IAM) systems to control user permissions.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in mastering containerization technologies like Docker and Kubernetes for IT efficiency.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop security awareness training programs to protect employees from social engineering.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to translate operational requirements into technical specifications for IT teams.</t></si><si><t>I want to monitor network traffic performance metrics to optimize the end-user experience.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in ensuring organizational compliance with data privacy laws like GDPR and HIPAA.</t></si><si><t>I want to manage relational and non-relational database systems to ensure data integrity.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to implement Security Information and Event Management (SIEM) for real-time monitoring.</t></si><si><t>I want to analyze data flows to ensure seamless integration between different enterprise applications.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing zero-trust network security architectures for modern businesses.</t></si><si><t>I want to lead IT service desks to resolve technical issues and maintain high user satisfaction.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>STEM PATHWAY 3. Civil Engineering -</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> High Scientific Ability and Visual Manipulative Skills with a Strong Inclination for Infrastructure Planning and Large-Scale Physical Design. This reflects an interest in applied physics, sustainable design, and construction oversight (Realistic &amp; Investigative).</t></r></si><si><t>Construction Management, Infrastructure, Environmental Engineering, System Engineering, Actuarial Science</t></si><si><t>Physics 1 &amp; 2,Chemistry 1 &amp; 2,  Earth &amp; Space Science 1 &amp; 2, Finite Math</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Construction Operation, Sustainable Construction, Infrastructure Design, Technical Drafting, Visual graphic Design, Illustration, Computer Programing ( Java, .net, or oracle)  </t></si><si><t>I want to manage large-scale construction projects and ensure structural safety from design to completion.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing essential public infrastructure such as bridges and mass transit systems.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop sustainable solutions for urban water resources and wastewater treatment.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by geotechnical analysis to ensure stable foundations for heavy structures.</t></si><si><t>I want to conduct environmental impact assessments to ensure eco-friendly urban development.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in using Building Information Modeling (BIM) for 3D simulation of civil works.</t></si><si><t>I want to plan efficient transportation systems and design intelligent traffic control networks.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to design resilient distribution networks for clean drinking water in municipalities.</t></si><si><t>I want to implement earthquake retrofitting techniques to improve the resilience of old buildings.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in utilizing GIS for site planning and monitoring topographical changes.</t></si><si><t>I want to manage construction site safety and supervise labor to ensure regulatory compliance.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in studying urban hydrology to manage storm runoff and prevent flooding.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop smart-city infrastructure that incorporates green spaces and renewable energy.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to research and test low-carbon concrete and recycled materials for construction.</t></si><si><t>I want to manage occupational health and safety protocols at large-scale engineering sites.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in coastal engineering to protect urban structures against rising sea levels.</t></si><si><t>I want to assess slope stability and soil mechanics to prevent landslides in mountainous regions.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing municipal landfill systems that minimize soil and water contamination.</t></si><si><t>I want to analyze wind and seismic loads to ensure the stability of ultra-tall skyscrapers.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in managing public-private partnerships for financing large public works.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">STEM PATHWAY 4. Mechanical Engineering </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>- High aptitude in Mathematical Ability and Scientific Ability with a Strong Inclination for Engineering Mechanics, Robotics, and Manufacturing Processes. This points to a preference for designing, building, and optimizing tangible mechanical products (Realistic &amp; Investigative).</t></r></si><si><t>Manufacturing,Geodetic Engineering,  Automotive, Robotics, Energy Systems,Construction Engineering &amp; Management</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">General Physics 1 &amp; 2, General Chemistry 1 &amp; 2, Finite Mathematics 1 &amp;2, Earth and Space Science 1 &amp;2, </t></si><si><t>Automotive Servicing, Mechatronics, Robotics &amp; Automation, Advanced Manufacturing, Manual Metal Arc Welding, Technical Drafting, Photovoltaic System Installation, Computer Programing ( Java, .net, or oracle) , Electronics Product Assembly and Servicing</t></si><si><t>I want to design and optimize automated production lines for industrial manufacturing.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in engineering fuel-efficient engines and studying thermodynamic cycles.</t></si><si><t>I want to integrate advanced sensors and control logic for autonomous robotic systems.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by thermal power generation systems and energy conversion devices.</t></si><si><t>I want to use CAD and Finite Element Analysis (FEA) to perform stress tests on new products.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in mechatronics, the synergy of mechanical, electrical, and computer systems.</t></si><si><t>I want to optimize the performance of fluid machinery such as pumps and turbines.</t></si><si><t>I am keen on using 3D printing and additive manufacturing for rapid hardware prototyping.</t></si><si><t>I want to research composite materials and metal alloys to create more durable components.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing biomedical devices such as robotic prosthetics and implants.</t></si><si><t>I want to solve heat transfer problems to protect electronics and industrial machinery.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to develop high-performance control systems for autonomous vehicle navigation.</t></si><si><t>I want to design mechanical components for renewable energy systems like wind turbines.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in simulating multi-body dynamics to predict how complex machines will move.</t></si><si><t>I want to ensure mechanical safety through failure analysis and non-destructive testing (NDT).</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing high-pressure vessels and piping for chemical and oil industries.</t></si><si><t>I want to study mechanical vibrations to reduce noise and wear in consumer products.</t></si><si><t>I am keen on developing soft robotics using smart materials that change shape with stimulus.</t></si><si><t>I want to optimize combustion efficiency in engines to reduce harmful environmental emissions.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in performing life-cycle assessments (LCA) to minimize manufacturing waste.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">STEM PATHWAY 5. Electrical Engineering </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>- High aptitude in Scientific Ability and Logical Reasoning with a Strong Inclination for Power Systems, Telecommunications, and Circuit Design. This suggests a core interest in the control and application of electrical energy and information transfer (Investigative &amp; Realistic).</t></r></si><si><t>Power Systems, Electronics, Telecommunications, Industrial Engineering, Systems Engineering</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">General Physics 1 &amp; 2, General Chemistry 1 &amp; 2, Finite Mathematics, </t></si><si><t>Electronics product Assembly and Servicing, Mechatronics, Electrical System Installation, Manual, Metal Arc Welding, Power Systems, Electronic Design,  Computer Programing ( Java, .net, or oracle)</t></si><si><t>I want to design and manage the electrical power grid and smart-grid integration technologies.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing integrated circuits and microprocessors for modern electronics.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop next-generation communication protocols for fiber optics and wireless systems.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by control systems and automation logic for industrial robotics.</t></si><si><t>I want to analyze electromagnetic wave propagation for satellite and cellular communication.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in power electronics for electric vehicle (EV) charging and battery systems.</t></si><si><t>I want to work on Very Large Scale Integration (VLSI) design for high-performance chips.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to develop Digital Signal Processing (DSP) algorithms for audio and video tools.</t></si><si><t>I want to monitor and control large utility processes using SCADA and industrial networks.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in antenna design and radio frequency (RF) engineering for high-speed data.</t></si><si><t>I want to design precision analog circuits and signal filters for scientific measurement.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in conducting energy audits and optimizing building electrical efficiency.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop hardware components for the future of quantum computing.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to mitigate electromagnetic interference (EMI) in sensitive medical electronics.</t></si><si><t>I want to program microcontrollers to manage sensors and actuators in robotic projects.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing high-voltage substations and transformer distribution networks.</t></si><si><t>I want to implement secure telecommunication protocols to protect critical infrastructure.</t></si><si><t>I am keen on creating advanced instrumentation for laboratory and industrial sensing.</t></si><si><t>I want to use machine learning for predictive maintenance of national electrical grids.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in optoelectronics, using lasers and LEDs for high-speed communication.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>STEM PATHWAY 6.  Nursing -</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> High scores in Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension with a Strong Inclination for Direct Patient Care, Wellness Advocacy, and Community Health. This aligns with a drive for social service, communication, and hands-on medical assistance (Social).</t></r></si><si><t>Healthcare, Medical Services, Public Health, Nutrition and Dietetics, Psychology, Physical Therapy (BSPT) / Occupational Therapy (BSOT), Respiratory Therapy, Social Work</t></si><si><t>Chemistry 1 - 4, Biology 1-4, Field Exposure, Safety and First Aid, Research Methods, Empowerment Technologies, Work Immersion</t></si><si><t>Caregiving (Child Care), Caregiving (Adult care)</t></si><si><t>I am committed to providing holistic, evidence-based patient care for recovery and comfort.</t></si><si><t>I want to specialize in critical care nursing to monitor patients in high-stakes environments.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in educating the community on health prevention and wellness advocacy.</t></si><si><t>I want to manage trauma responses and medical care in international disaster relief efforts.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to conduct clinical research that improves nursing protocols and patient safety.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in geriatric nursing to support the unique health needs of aging populations.</t></si><si><t>I want to provide mental health support and therapeutic communication for psychiatric patients.</t></si><si><t>I am keen on working in school health to manage pediatric wellness and immunization.</t></si><si><t>I want to master nursing informatics to improve patient charting and data accuracy.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in becoming a Nurse Practitioner to diagnose and treat patients independently.</t></si><si><t>I want to coordinate hospital disaster preparedness plans for pandemics or mass casualties.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to educate chronic disease patients on self-management and drug adherence.</t></si><si><t>I want to specialize in oncology nursing, providing clinical and emotional support to cancer patients.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in leading nursing units as a manager to ensure efficient staff operations.</t></si><si><t>I want to specialize in neonatal intensive care (NICU) to provide support for newborns.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to promote maternal and child health through postpartum and prenatal care.</t></si><si><t>I want to focus on occupational health nursing to protect the safety of workers in factories.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing public health vaccination campaigns to reduce infectious diseases.</t></si><si><t>I want to provide skilled medical care to patients within their private home environments.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to use my clinical expertise as a legal nurse consultant for medical lawsuits.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>STEM PATHWAY 7. Medical Technology / Medical Laboratory Science -</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> High aptitude in Scientific Ability and Attention to Detail with a Strong Inclination for Laboratory Diagnostics and Clinical Analysis. This is indicative of a disciplined interest in investigative research, precision testing, and medical support (Investigative &amp; Conventional).</t></r></si><si><t>Clinical Laboratory, Diagnostics, Research, Radiologic Technology, Environmental and Sanitary Engineering</t></si><si><t>Biology 1 &amp;2, Chemistry 1 &amp;2, Physics 1 &amp;2, Safety and First Aid, Fundamentals of data Analytics, Data management, Research Methods, Empowerment Technologies</t></si><si><t>Illustration,Computer Programming (Java or .NET Technology), Visual Graphic Design / Animation,</t></si><si><t>I want to operate complex laboratory analyzers for clinical blood and chemical testing.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in interpreting lab results to help doctors diagnose various medical conditions.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop and validate laboratory tests for newly emerging viral pathogens.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in blood banking and ensuring the safety and compatibility of transfusions.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to maintain strict quality control and assurance in high-volume medical labs.</t></si><si><t>I want to use molecular diagnostics and PCR to identify genetic mutations and cancer.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in identifying clinical bacteria and determining their antibiotic resistance.</t></si><si><t>I want to perform toxicology screenings to measure therapeutic drug levels and poisons.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in managing laboratory automation and ensuring efficient sample workflows.</t></si><si><t>I want to examine tissue and cell samples under the microscope to detect cancer.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in analyzing body fluids like spinal and pleural fluid for disease markers.</t></si><si><t>I want to specialize in endocrine testing and measuring metabolic hormone levels.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by the morphology of blood cells and the science of clotting disorders.</t></si><si><t>I want to evaluate new diagnostic platforms and automation technologies for efficiency.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in validating new lab equipment to meet federal CLIA standards.</t></si><si><t>I want to research how the immune system reacts to diseases through serological testing.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in screening blood donations for infectious markers and safety.</t></si><si><t>I want to manage Point-of-Care Testing (POCT) in remote clinics and ambulances.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in clinical parasitology and identifying parasites in medical specimens.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to maintain strict biosafety levels when handling hazardous infectious agents.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">STEM PATHWAY 8. Pharmacy </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>- High scores in Scientific Ability and Verbal Ability with a Strong Inclination for Drug Research, Medication Management, and Healthcare Consultation. This highlights a dual interest in the chemical science of drugs and patient interaction/education (Investigative &amp; Social).</t></r></si><si><t>Pharmaceuticals, Drug Research, Healthcare, Clinical Research, Health Information Management (HIM), Healthcare Administration / Management, Health Data Analytics</t></si><si><t>Pre-Calculus, Physics 1 &amp; 2, Chemistry 1 &amp; 2, Biology 1 &amp; 2, Finite Mathematics 1 &amp;2, Business 1 &amp;2</t></si><si><t>Medical transcription,Computer Programming (Java or .NET Technology) Visual Graphic Design / Animation,</t></si><si><t>I am interested in the discovery of new drug molecules and their effects on the body.</t></si><si><t>I want to work in a clinical setting to optimize drug therapy for individual patients.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to provide clear medication counseling to patients about side effects and use.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in industrial pharmacy and the large-scale manufacturing of capsules and tablets.</t></si><si><t>I want to conduct pharmacoeconomic studies to determine the cost-benefit of new drugs.</t></si><si><t>I am keen on monitoring drug-drug interactions and patient safety in a hospital pharmacy.</t></si><si><t>I want to perform pharmaceutical compounding for patients with unique medication needs.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in pharmacovigilance and monitoring long-term drug safety in the public.</t></si><si><t>I want to specialize in veterinary pharmacy to provide medications for various animal species.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in managing a community pharmacy and leading public health initiatives.</t></si><si><t>I want to research pharmacogenomics to tailor medications to a person's genetic profile.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in developing innovative drug delivery systems like nanotech or patches.</t></si><si><t>I want to work in pharmaceutical regulatory affairs to ensure drugs meet national standards.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in pharmacy informatics to use technology for preventing medication errors.</t></si><si><t>I want to design and oversee clinical trials to test the safety of experimental medications.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in geriatric pharmacy to manage polypharmacy in elderly patients.</t></si><si><t>I want to work in a poison control center to provide expert toxicity and overdose info.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in nuclear pharmacy and the preparation of radioactive diagnostic agents.</t></si><si><t>I want to research pharmacognosy, the study of drugs derived from natural plant sources.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to educate physicians and nurses on proper medication reconciliation steps.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">STEM PATHWAY 9. Biology - </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> High Scientific Ability and Moderate Inclination for Research, paired with a Strong Interest in Life Sciences, Biotechnology, and Environmental Studies. This is characteristic of a student interested in fundamental scientific inquiry and biological systems (Investigative).</t></r></si><si><t>Biotechnology, Environmental Science, Pre-Medicine, Molecular Biology,Biostatistics / Epidemiology, Nutrition and Dietetics, Health Information Management, Environmental and Sanitary Engineering</t></si><si><t>Biology 1 -4, Chemistry 1 &amp;2, Physics 1 &amp;2, Pre-calculus and calculus,   Empowerment Technologies, Research Methods</t></si><si><t>Caregiving (Child Care), Caregiving (Adult care), Medical transcription, Computer Programming,</t></si><si><t>I want to manipulate biological systems at the genetic level to develop GMOs for society.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in studying diverse ecosystems and developing wildlife conservation plans.</t></si><si><t>I want to study human physiology and disease mechanisms to prepare for medical school.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to conduct laboratory research on microbial genetics and biotechnology.</t></si><si><t>I want to use DNA sequencing and genetic fingerprinting to solve criminal investigations.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in marine biology and the impact of climate change on coral reefs.</t></si><si><t>I want to research molecular biology to understand cellular communication and organelles.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in epidemiology and studying how infectious diseases spread in populations.</t></si><si><t>I want to study plant biology to improve agricultural yields and food security.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in ecological restoration and returning damaged lands to health.</t></si><si><t>I want to research the brain and neural mechanisms that lead to mental disorders.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to develop sustainable biofuels using plant biology and genetic engineering.</t></si><si><t>I want to work in forensic labs analyzing biological evidence like blood and hair.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in learning detailed human anatomy through medical-grade dissection.</t></si><si><t>I want to study paleontology and trace the evolutionary history of vertebrates through fossils.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in environmental toxicology and how industrial chemicals affect life.</t></si><si><t>I want to research animal behavior to improve conservation strategies for endangered species.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in using bioinformatics software to map and analyze the human genome.</t></si><si><t>I want to research developmental biology and how cells form complex living organisms.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in researching the human gut microbiome and its impact on nutrition.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">STEM PATHWAY 10. Chemistry - </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>High aptitude in Scientific Ability and Logical Reasoning with a Strong Inclination for Chemical Analysis, Material Synthesis, and Industrial Quality Control. This suggests a primary interest in the structure and transformation of matter (Investigative &amp; Realistic).</t></r></si><si><t>Industrial Chemistry, Research, Quality Control, Medical Technology / Medical Laboratory Science, Radiologic Technology, Environmental and Sanitary Engineering, Nutrition and Dietetics, Biochemistry</t></si><si><t>Chemistry 1 - 4, Physics 1 &amp;2, Pre-calculus and calculus, Biology 1 &amp;2, research methods, Physics 1 &amp;2, Empowerment Technologies</t></si><si><t>Aesthetic Services, Food Processing, Organic Agriculture Production, Computer Systems Servicing, Computer Programming (.NET or Java)</t></si><si><t>I want to optimize chemical processes for the production of polymers and fuels.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in using spectroscopy and chromatography for chemical quality control.</t></si><si><t>I want to design and synthesize complex organic molecules for the drug industry.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in environmental chemistry and monitoring water and soil pollution.</t></si><si><t>I want to use chemical thermodynamics to improve the efficiency of industrial yields.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in chemical testing for food safety and nutritional certification.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop new chemical catalysts for cleaner energy-efficient manufacturing.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by polymer science and developing new durable plastics and fibers.</t></si><si><t>I want to research inorganic chemistry to create next-generation battery materials.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in forensic chemistry and identifying trace evidence from crime scenes.</t></si><si><t>I want to work in fragrance and flavor chemistry to formulate new consumer products.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in astrochemistry and analyzing the molecular components of deep space.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop green chemistry methods that reduce hazardous waste in manufacturing.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in managing industrial chemical safety and hazardous waste compliance.</t></si><si><t>I want to conduct quality control testing on the purity of pharmaceutical raw materials.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in atmospheric chemistry and studying the effects of gases on ozone.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop new surface coatings and industrial paints with heat-resistant properties.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to improve the energy efficiency of chemical reactors in heavy industry.</t></si><si><t>I want to research electrochemistry for the development of clean hydrogen fuel cells.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in formulating cosmetics and testing their safety and stability for skin.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">STEM PATHWAY 11. Mathematics / Statistics </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> - Excellent standing in Mathematical Ability and Logical Reasoning with a Strong Inclination for Abstract Modeling, Data Quantification, and Financial/Risk Analysis. This shows a preference for theoretical and applied quantitative reasoning (Investigative &amp; Conventional).</t></r></si><si><t>Applied Mathematics, Accountancy, Data Analysis, Actuarial Science, Education, Finance, Physics</t></si><si><t>Finite Mathematics 1&amp;2, Trigonometry 1 &amp;2, Chemistry 1 &amp;2, Physics 1 &amp;2, Pre-calculus and calculus, Empowerment Technologies, Biology 1 &amp;2,  research methods,</t></si><si><t>Computer Programming (.NET or Java), Computer Systems Servicing</t></si><si><t>I want to use statistical learning to find patterns in massive datasets.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in applying probability to calculate financial risks for insurance.</t></si><si><t>I am passionate about math pedagogy and finding new ways to teach abstract concepts.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop quantitative models for analyzing stock markets and financial trends.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in pure mathematics research, focusing on number theory or topology.</t></si><si><t>I want to specialize in Bayesian statistics to design more accurate scientific trials.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to become a certified actuary to manage pension and insurance liabilities.</t></si><si><t>I want to use operations research to solve logistics and resource allocation problems.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in using differential equations to model physical and biological systems.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop and test algorithms for automated high-frequency trading.</t></si><si><t>I am fascinated by graph theory and its use in analyzing social and internet networks.</t></si><si><t>I want to work in biostatistics to design and analyze outcomes of medical trials.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in using computer simulations to help students visualize math concepts.</t></si><si><t>I want to apply game theory to analyze competition and decision-making in economics.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in exploring the formal logic and set theory that underpin mathematics.</t></si><si><t>I want to use time-series analysis for forecasting climate changes or market trends.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to research abstract algebra and its applications in digital coding theory.</t></si><si><t>I want to apply linear algebra and numerical methods to solve large-scale engineering problems.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in geometry and topology for designing smooth curves in CAD tools.</t></si><si><t>I am passionate about coaching students for high-level math and logic competitions.</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">STEM PATHWAY 12. Education major in Sciences - </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="12"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Arial"/><family val="2"/></rPr><t>High Verbal Ability and Reading Comprehension with a Strong Inclination for STEM Teaching, Mentorship, and Curriculum Development. This reflects a passion for academic content delivery and social influence in an educational setting (Social &amp; Investigative).</t></r></si><si><t>STEM Teaching, Curriculum Development, Educational Leadership</t></si><si><t>Chemistry 1&amp;2, Physics 1 &amp;2, Pre-calculus and calculus, Biology 1 &amp;2, research methods, Physics 1 &amp;2, Empowerment Technologies</t></si><si><t>animation, Illustration, Visual Graphic Design</t></si><si><t>I want to make complex scientific concepts accessible to high school students.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing interdisciplinary STEM curricula that integrate technology.</t></si><si><t>I want to mentor science teachers and lead academic science departments in schools.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in using digital tools and interactive simulations for science learning.</t></si><si><t>I want to conduct educational research to measure the effectiveness of science teaching.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to develop inquiry-based science labs for hands-on student discovery.</t></si><si><t>I want to evaluate textbooks and lab equipment to ensure they meet modern standards.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in reducing educational disparities in STEM for underserved students.</t></si><si><t>I want to design science outreach programs for science centers and museums.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to facilitate professional development workshops for STEM educators.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in designing school projects that connect biology, chemistry, and engineering.</t></si><si><t>I want to serve as a school administrator to integrate STEM principles across all grades.</t></si><si><t>I want to develop assessments that measure conceptual understanding, not just memory.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in coaching students for science fairs and robotics competitions.</t></si><si><t>I want to use educational neuroscience to improve student memory and retention in science.</t></si><si><t>I want to partner with local industries to bring real-world science to the classroom.</t></si><si><t>I am driven to lead the creation of culturally relevant science curricula for diverse schools.</t></si><si><t>I am interested in researching the use of VR and AR tools for immersive science education.</t></si><si><t>I want to lead advocacy efforts to increase state funding for school science labs.</t></si><si><t>I am passionate about developing students' ability to communicate complex science clearly.</t></si></sst>